Anne Nivethitha Diana

Senior Digital Marketing Specialist Marketing and Demand Generation

\bowtie	annenive@gmail.com
	+91 9789876145,
in	@AnneNivethithaDiana

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

10 years of experience within marketing communications, digital media, and Information Technology background. I have harnessed all channels to create valuable tools for brand awareness and optimal experiences for varying target audiences.

Extensive expertise in branding, development of integrated marketing programs, digital innovation, research, creative development and product/service launches. Delivering strong results through the whole process, from PR & digital marketing strategies to the creative side of user experience and design.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Consistently increased brand awareness through a uniform brand message.
- Training, communications and adoption of technology initiatives to + 65,000 users worldwide.
- Award for developing a HR Video in quick span of time with great Quality and Output.
- Planned, designed and conducted the company's anniversary event.
- Implemented two successful employee engagement programs

EXPERIENCE

Senior Digital Marketing Specialist

Volteo Digital, September 2021 - Present

SEO and Marketing Activities:

- Designed and developed a new brand of solutions and corporate website.
- Develop optimization strategies that increase the company's search engine results rankings.
- Update content and website links for maximum optimization and search engine rankings.
- Design and launch email marketing campaigns.
- Design and deliver media relations content, white papers, executive bios, corporate newsletter and social media content.

Marketing & Corporate Communication Specialist

Volteo Digital, August 2018 - August 2021

Corporate Communications Activities:

- Create wireframes, user flows, process flows and site maps to effectively communicate interaction and design ideas using Figma
- Designed and developed the corporate site for the transformation of the new brand and identity.
- Develop the corporate site and brand for the Volteo group companies Volteo Maritime; and Volteo Edge.
- Design and implement the total rewards strategy to develop a workforce motivated toward excellence in the organization.
- Design and develop the communications plan to launch the Global Employee Recognition Program.
- Design graphic visuals for internal programs, presentations, and social media.

Senior IT Communications Specialist

• Flex, November 2012 – July 2018

Internal communications and multimedia executions:

- Develop and maintain UI/branding design and strategy for corporate intranet websites.
- Publish, coordinate and design the first quarterly global IT newsletter that reached more than 23,000 readers throughout all company segments.
- Developed a print/web collateral and marketing campaign materials for the first Global IT Summit event.
- Design CIO All hands and CEO update quarterly communication messages.

Web brand management and IT messaging:

- Develop, deliver and manage communications for local sites about corporate initiatives.
- Create and maintain a visual system that supports the Flex brand across all web and mobile applications.
- Developed the marketing materials, including website development and maintenance to promote mobile app development and transform the landscape of IT solutions into mobile experiences.
- Design and develop e-learning solutions for corporate applications using Adobe Captivate.

CERTIFICATIONS

- LinkedIn Marketing Solutions Fundamentals
- <u>HubSpot Digital Marketing</u>
- Google Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGY

- Expert with design software tools: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Adobe XD, Figma.
- Business and creative skills: Advertising, Branding, dynamic content management.
- Reporting and analytics: Google Analytics, MailChimp, Campaign Monitor.
- Web: Content management systems (WordPress, Without Code, SharePoint),
 Typeform, HTML + CSS, Email marketing.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree (M.C.A)

Bharathidasan University, Centre for Distance Education, April 2014

Bachelor of Computer Applications (B.C.A)

Stella Maris College, University of Madras, April 2012

LANGUAGES

English, Tamil, French (to read)

I hereby declare that the above data are true to the best of my knowledge.

Yours Truly,
Anne Nivethitha Diana.A

Place: Chennai